STEPHAN DURRY

An analytics enthusiast who aims to create successful data teams via a modern & lean tech stack, I started my career in publishing before moving into digital media & the Berlin startup.

Currently and for the past 3 years, I have been with Onefootball, the world's biggest soccer stats & news platform and home to more than 10 million monthly users. While providing insights for business-critical decision-making, I lead a team powered by an environment of open feedback, trust and individual development.



WORK EXPERIENCE

today | 2019-10 Head of Data & Insights Onefootball

Berlin, DE

Management of a multi-talented team across 3 disciplines - Analysis, Data Engineering & Data Science. I inform and deliver insights to peer stakeholders and C-Level on a weekly basis. My growing responsibility includes an increasing focus on acquiring premium talent in the field of machine learning dedicated to the development of NLP and recommender systems.

2019-09 | 2017-07 Data Lead Onefootball

Berlin, DE

Responsible for setting up the basic analytics infrastructure at Onefootball with a small team of Data Engineers, processing 15bln events monthly. I introduced first frameworks for ETL and data modeling which fed area-specific dashboards for newsroom and marketing departments, among other teams. Editors were able to improve weekday retention by 3ppt due to better user segmentation.

2017-06

2016-03

2013-04

2012-03

Business Analyst Onefootball

Page Berlin, DE

Executive Assistant to CEO

Motor Presse

Madrid, ES

My first job taught me a lot about stakeholder management and communication. Preparing and debriefing internal and external meetings fostered routines that I use on a daily basis even today. I also contributed in the development of a digital media strategy for publishing brands across different geos.



EDUCATION

2015-03 | 2013-04 M.Sc Econometrics RWTH Aachen

Aachen, DE

2010-03 | 2007-08 B.Sc Business Administration University of Cologne

Cologne, DE



CONTACT

■ stephan.durry@gmail.com
 in sdurry

J +49 175 2679086

ANALYTICS SKILLS

Languages: German, English, Spanish (all fluent)

Coding Languages: R, Python, SQL

Data Stack: dbt, airflow, AWS (Glue, Redshift Spectrum, S3), Metabase, Tableau

Analytics & Insights: Customer Analytics, Content Performance, CLTV Modeling

Engineering: ETL, Data Lake Infrastructure, Data Testing, Workflow Orchestration

Source code is available on github.

Last updated on 2020-01-24.